Lee W. Stanley Papers
Lee W. Stanley Papers
1906-1964
1930-1957
Stanley, Lee Wright
5 linear ft.
Original cartoons, proofs, newspaper clippings, photos and published material of the American cartoonist, most from his syndicated panel "The Old Home Town."
2653502
Biographical History
Lee Wright Stanley (b. 1885) was an American cartoonist and creator of the comic strip The Old Home Town.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lee W. Stanley Papers contains cartoons (original art and proof sheets), memorabilia, and printed material.
The vast majority of Cartoons consist of original art and proof sheets for Stanley's syndicated one-panel The Old Home Town (1930-1964). A detailed listing of the exact dates for which we have original art is available. The proof sheets, which are in two different sizes, each contain one week's worth of panels (Monday through Saturday); there is no detailed listing for the dates of the proof sheets but in most cases the entire year is present. The few other items in this series are original art for a few political cartoons relating to conventions (1912 and 1928) and some miscellaneous cartoons.
Memorabilia contains clippings about Stanley, a biographical sketch and essay on his career, and photographs of Stanley and his wife, Harriet, who assisted him on The Old Home Town.
Printed material contains clippings of Stanley's work, including some World War I cartoons, and a booklet entitled "Guide to Good Humor," produced and illustrated by Stanley and several other cartoonists.
Arrangement of the Collection
All other material is in alphabetical order. Within the cartoon series, proof sheets are arranged in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Stanley, Lee Wright.; Old Home Town (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Mountain people -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs.; Proofs (printed matter); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lee W. Stanley, 1967.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  - "The Old Home Town"
    - Character sheets, photocopies, showing all the characters from the strip (Box 1)
    - Original art, 11" x 11"
      Click here for detailed inventory.
      - 1930, 13" x 14.5" (Oversize 8)
      - 1931-1935 (Oversize 1)
      - 1936-1940, 1942, 1945, 1947-1948, 1951, 1958 (Oversize 2)
      - 1959 (Oversize 3)
      - 1960-Jun 1961 (Oversize 4)
      - Jul 1961-1962 (Oversize 5)
    - Proof sheets, most on newsprint, two different sizes
      - 1926, 10" x 14" (Box 1)
      - 1937-1944, 14" x 20" (Oversize 6)
      - 1944, 10" x 14" (Box 1)
      - 1945, 10" x 14" (Box 1)
      - 1945-1957, 14" x 20" (Oversize 7)
      - 1948-1962, 15 folders 10" x 14" (Box 1)
      - 1963-1964, 2 folders 10" x 14" (Box 2)
  - Political conventions, 1912; 1928; original art (Oversize 8)
  - Miscellaneous cartoons, 1906-1907; undated; original art (Oversize 8)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings about, 1928; 1930,; 1957,; 1963,; undated (Box 2)
  - "Lee Stanley, Cartoonist", 1986 (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Stanley, family, friends, 1923; 1927,; 1949,; 1952,; 1950,; 1963 (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - Cleveland Press clippings, 1913 (Box 2)
  - "Guide to Good Humor", 1945 (Box 2)
  - LIFE magazine cartoons, 1902-1903 (Box 2)
  - World War I cartoons, 1915 and later (Box 2)